{
  "reference_number": "1892",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a goal to reach net zero emissions by the second half of the century and the Climate Change Commission advises on the specific target for the Government to set later",
      "answer_index": 11,
      "notes": "Sooner the better!"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "Set a bold target, and work hard to get it. Methane absolutely should be included!"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "Emissions trading is a joke. One country can pollute more if they buy credits off a country that meets its reduction target? NO! If a\n\n country doesn't meet reduction targets there should be no way out! get heavy handed. Even by applying sanctions on them"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The only change should be to make the target sooner."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "Only change should be to target less emissions"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Only change should be to target less emissions"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "I don't care about the economy so much. I'd rather us go back to recession times and see more people sleeping in cars etc than\n\nmiss our target, or make a laughably small reduction target. Social and economic circumstances should be pushed to the limit, and\nnay sayers told to harden up. I hope to see fuel rise to 5, 6, 7 dollars a litre to force people into buying EVs. and the govt could make\nit easier on us to buy EVs, eg. by wiping GST, while increasing GST on petrol vehicles Technology should be at the forefront of\n\nemission reduction planning. The Govt should subsidise things like solar panels for homes and ban power companies from\nintroducing things like 'solar taxes'. Set requirements for all new home builds to have solar panels by 2030 etc"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We need to work with everyone: farmers, industial sector, public. But in a way that is forceful, so we don't give in and neglect targets.\n\nIe, work to set up incentives and make solid plans for the future, but at the same time holding to account the weak areas. for\nexample, work with farmers to help build fences to keep cattle away from rivers and build a policy around it. perhaps subsidise the\n\ncost of their fencing. but introduce crippling fines for any farmer that doesn't abide."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "should have decision making power"
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We need to be heavy handed. People are too selfish to take initiative and help the cause. We'll never make our targets if theres no\n\nconsequences set out. But while there are consequences, there should also be incentives and rewards to encourage change\nacross all of our emissions sectors. As an example I'd love it if the idea of getting a bank loan to buy a $20,000 EV was actually a\n\ncheaper and more easily achievable long term option than owning a petrol vehicle for New Zealanders. Maybe the govt could work\nwith banks to provide lower interest rate loans for anyone buying an EV? No GST on EVs, while increasing GST on petrol cars to 30%.\nWorking with power companies to provide lower electricity rates for charging EVs at home etc.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
